《僵尸国度》前情提要
Previously on Z Nation.
还有谁也在担忧着那位"阳光先生"呢
Anybody else worried about Mr. Sunshine out there?
我知道  看来他的状况每况愈下
I know. He's looking worse.
你是什么东西
What are you?
僵尸怎么不攻击你
Why didn't it attack you?
你们又不想咬我  你们想干什么
You don't want to eat me. What do you want?
我不是重生者之一
I am not one of the resurrected.
我才是你们的救世主
I'm your messiah.
科罗拉多州  南方公园
你觉得我们是不是再也见不到他们了
Do you think we'll ever see them again?
麦克和艾迪吗
Mack and Addy?
我内心的回答是肯定的
My heart says yes.
但我的大脑
But my mind?
回答是否定的
My mind says no.
应许之地出自圣经故事  通俗理解为怀抱希望之所
我还真希望他们能跟我们一起到达应许之地呢
I was kinda hoping they'd make it with us to the promise land.
又搞什么呢
Now what?
注意一下  各位
Heads up, everybody.
我讨厌路障
I hate roadblocks.
你就不能把那些玩意撞开吗
Can't you just push that thing out of our way?
谢了  这车姐还打算要呢
No thanks. I'd like to hold onto this truck.
这片高尔夫球场看上去可不咋地啊
Well this golf course has seen better days.
这还真可悲
This is so sad.
我之前在牢里学着怎么打
I learned to play in prison.
曾经幻想有朝一日能去
Always wondered what it'd be like
真正的乡村俱乐部打一场该会是怎样
to hang out with the real country club types.
你觉得那个桥能承受住这车的重量吗
Think that bridge is gonna hold this truck?
最好还是先检验一下
Better test it first.
看上去挺坚固的
Looks pretty solid.
你好  三角洲X光小队
Hello, Delta-Xray.
市民Z现在呼叫全体成员  呼叫全体成员
Citizen Z calling all cars, calling all cars.
这里是三角洲X光小队
Delta-Xray back at you.
你们好啊  很高兴能再次听到你们的声音
Hello, good to hear from you again.
有段日子没联络了  我担心你们
It's been days, and I worry.
谢谢您了  大娘
Thanks, mom.
有任何麦克和艾迪的新动向吗
Any news on Mack or Addy?
没  还没有
No, nothing yet.
也许因为他们那边没有网  无法联络吧
Maybe they're just off the grid and can't make contact.
也许吧
Maybe.
摩菲怎么样了
How's Murphy?
摩菲很生气后果很严重
Murphy is pissed.
你嘴里一直说的那个鬼实验室到底在哪
Where the hell is that lab you keep talking about?
你难道没发现那个巫医差点害死我吗
And have you found that witch doctor that almost killed me?
那个莫奇医生
Doctor Merch?
这事儿我还在努力调查中
I'm still working on that.
还有  你自称是国安局的是吧
And you call yourself the NSA?
别再看A片了好吗  赶紧找出那个江湖郎中
Quit looking at porn and find that quack.
我们现在有正事要解决
We got business to settle.
这人还真"好"相处
Such a nice guy.
右面那个我来解决
I got the one on the right.
第2455个
Two thousand, four hundred fifty-five.
我没子弹了
I'm out of ammo.
我也没了
Me too.
快看  有高尔夫球棒
Look. Some clubs.
别拿那些破推杆啊
Not the putter.
记住要保持你的左臂笔直挥出
Remember keep your left arm straight.
我们赶紧往俱乐部那边跑吧
Let's run for the clubhouse!
摩菲呢
Murphy?
他还在外面某处吧
He's out there somewhere.
起码比我们安全
Safer than us.
我们来伴儿了
We got company.
这里挥不起来啊
Hard to swing in here!
小万万  射他
10K, your sling!
必须的
Yeah.
数量有点多
Too many.
往这边走
This way!
这门撑不了多久
Door won't hold much longer!
在这总比在外面强
Better in here than out there!
怎么有枪声
Gunfire?
你们可以出来了
You can come out now.
那声音不是摩菲的
That was not Murphy.
当然也不会是丧尸的
It wasn't a Z either.
行了  大伙准备好
All right, get ready.
没事了
It's okay.
我们都解决了
It's all clear.
你们来的真是时候
Nice timing.
别掉以轻心
Don't get too relaxed.
外面还有更多僵尸
There's still more outside.
我们的一个小伙伴也在外面
We got another guy outside too.
难以置信
I don't believe it.
从哪冒出来的熊孩子
Kid out of nowhere.
在圣安德鲁古城  这个高尔夫之乡
Final holes of the Open Championship
公开赛的最后一球
at historic Saint Andrews, home of golf.
他将会打出一个低飞球
He's gonna hit a knock-down seven.
哎呀可惜  他搞糟了
Oh, he got all of that!
抱歉
Sorry!
咋了
What?
你不觉得这么做有点危险吗
Little risky, don't you think?
不会  丧尸们爱我
No. The Zs love me.
你他妈是谁
Who the hell are you?
我是布雷特·兹莫曼
Brett Zimmerman.
他们是亨利和詹尼斯
This is Henry and Janice.
我是罗伯塔·沃伦
Roberta Warren.
他们是多克  一万  卡桑德拉
This is Doc, 10K, Cassandra, and
那个穿着夹克在和丧尸打高尔夫的白痴是摩菲
the fool with the jacket golfing with the zombies, that's Murphy.
你这是赤裸裸的嫉妒  就因为僵尸们更爱我
You're just jealous cuz they like me more than you.
圣诞快乐
即使还没到寒冬时节
Even though it's really not the season,
在这个周六夜晚  苍穹之下
it was the night before Sunday and all through the dome,
万物却一片沉寂
not a creature was stirring
和这首诗描绘的截然不同
in spite of this poem.
我在淘宝  浩博  雅虎和携程
So on Blingo, on Hotbot, go Yahoo and Kayak.
以及谷歌  科技和医药网站上寻寻觅觅
Search Google and Info and also NextBio.
搜寻玛丽莲·莫奇的踪迹
Find Marilyn Merch.
你去哪里了
Where have you gone?
你顺利抵达加利福尼亚了吗
Did you make it to California?
还是你也变成了丧尸
Or do you walk among the dead?
你口渴吗
Thirsty?
自打在朴茨茅斯上学起我就一直很渴
I have been since Portsmouth.
你是普林斯顿大学还是麻省理工的
Princeton? Massachusetts?
天呐
Christ.
我可是校友
I'm an alum.
又是一个前科犯
Another ex-con.
你不是吗
Not you?
僵尸病毒蔓延之前我一直在中学教英语
I taught junior high english before everything went to hell.
亨利则是在圣卡洛斯  我猜他走私毒品
But Henry was in San Carlos, drug smuggling I think.
我很欣赏的一类人
Hmmm, my kinda guy.
你怎么看
Your evaluation?
我从没见过这样的情况  僵尸似乎都怕他
I never saw anything like it. The Zs seemed afraid of him.
我们亲眼所见不会有假
But we saw what we saw.
这样的人才迟早能派上用场
Talent like that could come in handy.
别小气  多倒点才对嘛
Yeah, and let's not be stingy with that. There you go.
你成年了吗
Got any ID?
很不错  不是家酿白干那种烂货色
Mmmm. Oh yeah, this is not that White Lightning crap.
尝一口吧  一角小哥
Have a taste, 10 cent.
沃伦小姐
Miss Warren...
叫我罗伯塔
Roberta.
罗伯塔  你想敬个酒吗
Roberta, would you like to propose a toast?
好的
Sure.
敬没能在场的朋友们
To absent friends.
摩菲先生
Mr. Murphy.
你对付僵尸似乎很有自己的一套
You seem to have a special way with them.
兄弟你还真不清楚我的来历
Brother, you don't know the half of it.
少来了摩菲
Come on, Murphy.
没人想听你的战争破事
No one wants to hear your war stories.
是他们问起的
They asked.
我想听
I'd like to hear it.
那些看上去像是僵尸咬的
Those look like zombie bites.
一共八个伤疤
Eight of 'em.
我大难不死
And I lived to tell the tale.
这怎么可能
How is that possible?
我被注射了试验阶段的疫苗
Well I was given an experimental vaccine,
现在僵尸认为我是它们的一员
and now the Zs think I'm one of them.
还有这种疫苗吗
Is there more of this vaccine?
现在在你面前的  就是已知的唯一幸存者
You're looking at it. Only known survivor.
但是如果我们能到达加州的实验室
But if we can get to this lab in California,
他们就能用我血液中的抗体制作更多疫苗
they can make more vaccine using the antibodies in my blood.
人类就能生存下去
And the human race survives.
我们的朋友喜欢夸大其词
Our friend tends to exaggerate.
得了
Come on.
我们都看到他行走于僵尸之间不受攻击
We all saw him walk through zombies.
怎么说好呢  哥浑然天成
What can I say? I'm a natural.
你想不天成也不行啊
Try unnatural.
看来有人喝醉了哦
Somebody had a cocktail.
亨利  别忘了守在外面的那位朋友多克
Henry? Don't forget about our friend Doc outside.
他要去的加州实验室  路途遥远啊
So his lab in California, that's a long ways.
我们从纽约出发的
We started in New York.
纽约
New York?
你们从纽约来的吗
You came from New York?
路途艰难
Wasn't easy.
说得可真轻描淡写
That is an understatement.
我们本来要去西边
Well we were headed west.
也许剩下的路我们可以协助你们
Maybe we can help get you the rest of the way.
我们可以接受帮助
We could use the help.
请允许我再说一句祝酒词
Let me propose another toast.
敬加州
To California.
也好
Yeah.
敬加州
To California.
想瞄得更准吗
Steady your aim?
喝一小口应该没事
Oh, well maybe just a sip.
麻烦你告诉我的朋友一万  该他放哨了
Hey, tell my buddy 10K it's his turn to take watch.
不能再喝了
That last sip,
看来我比想象中更疲乏
I must be tired than I thought.
怎么回事
What's happening?
该死
Oh shit.
我在哪
Where am I?
我醒了
I'm awake.
好吧  大家坚持住
Okay, everybody hold on.
恐怕坚持不住
Not a great option right now.
摩菲呢
Where's Murphy?
摩菲
Murphy!
好吧
Okay.
有人看到什么尖锐的东西吗
Anyone see anything sharp?
地板上到处都是高尔夫球的球拖
Well there's all these golf tees on the floor.
太短了
Too short.
我压着什么  就在我身下  一万  摸出来
Well I got something under here. It's in my... 10K, get it.
摸到了吗
You got it? Ummm.
额  这个不够尖锐
Oh, no that's not sharp enough.
好吧
Okay, uh.
看那
Uh, oh look.
吧台上有东西
There's something on top of the bar.
快点
Any time!
好吧
Okay.
倒数三下
Ready? On three.
一
One!
二
Two!
三
Three!
很好
Okay.
现在
Now...
我们怎么脱身
How do we get out of these?
能破坏掉这串锁吗
Can we bust that rail?
如果不能  那肯定不是因为没努力
Well if we can't, it ain't gonna be for lack of tryin'.
你要是再敢说什么跟高尔夫有关的话
If you say anything golf-related,
姐就用这东西戳死你
I'll poke you with it.
你们要带我去哪
Where are you taking me?
在后排坐好  你应感激有这么好的条件
Just sit back and appreciate your improved circumstances.
抱歉  这哪里好了
I'm sorry. How is this an improvement?
我们有食物  水和燃料
We have food, water, fuel.
你和你的小伙伴们没有食物和水
You and your friends had no food, no water,
都已经精疲力竭了
and were running on fumes.
你们也没有子弹了
And no ammo.
感谢我们把你从那帮废物中解救出来吧
Should be thankful we freed you from those losers.
也许失去双手的自由
Well maybe losing the feelings in my hands
让我有些暴躁
is making me a little cranky.
我的意思是  这样有必要吗
I mean are these really necessary?
等等
Hey. Look.
我懂了
I get it.
你们听我说自己的事情
You heard me talking about my deal
然后决定插一脚
and decided to horn in.
觉得如果把我送到加利福尼亚
Figured there might be something in it for you
可能会有利可图
if you get me to California.
但是大伙  这得等到太阳从西边出来吧
But guys, unless the sun decided to rise in the west
因为我们走错了  加州在反方向
we're headed the wrong way. California's behind us.
我们不去加利福尼亚
We're not going to California.
那你们到底想干什么
What the hell do you want?
你为什么不能放松一下  享受风景呢
Why don't you just relax, enjoy the scenery?
我看够了
I already seen it.
那你就闭嘴
Then just try shutting up.
不吐槽不是我性格
Not my nature.
那就改性子
Then evolve.
不久后你就知道我们想要什么了
You'll find out what we want soon enough.
你们对其他人做了什么
What'd you do to the others?
他们不会任由你们把我带走
You know they won't just let you take me.
他们可比看起来要危险得多
They're a lot more dangerous than they look.
你不用再为他们操心了
You don't have to worry about them anymore.
你们做了什么
What'd you do?
杀了他们吗
You kill them?
我们把他们留给僵尸了
We left them for the Zs.
物竞天择  适者生存
Darwin will take care of the rest.
我们是怎么了
What happened to us?
我想我们被下药了
I believe we got roofied.
下的是安定剂
Drugged with rohypnol.
摩菲去哪了
Where's Murphy?
其他人也不见了
The others are gone too.
你不会想...
You don't think...
摩菲不会那么做
Murphy wouldn't do that.
难道下药后逃跑吗
Drug us to escape?
我们怎么可以让这样的事发生
How could we let this happen?
他是我们的职责所在
He was our responsibility.
至少他们还留了辆车
At least they left our ride.
电池没电了
The battery's dead.
假设我们可以继续前进
Well assuming we find some way to get moving,
接下来呢
what next, boss?
找摩菲  把他送到加利福尼亚
Go after Murphy and get his ass to California
或者死在找他的路上
or die tryin'.
我们知道他的行踪吗
Hey, do we even know what direction he went in?
多克  问题太多了  太多了
Too many questions, Doc. Too many questions.
这有电池  我不知道状态如何
It's got a battery. I don't know how good.
看这个
Look at this.
太好了
Yes.
你怎么知道会有这玩意的
How did you know that?
看到后面的天线了
Saw the antenna on the back.
信号传输
我在
I'm here.
摩菲丢了
We lost Murphy.
我的天
Holy crap.
这可能是个永久而巨大的悲剧
That has the potential for great, permanent tragedy.
我们猜他可能被三个市民绑架
We think he may have been kidnapped by three civilians,
动机不明
motive unknown.
但是他们知道摩菲的身份
But they are aware of Murphy's status.
他还活着吗  你们清楚吗
Is he still alive? Do you know if Murphy is still alive?
据我们所知  是的
As far as we know.
他今早不见踪影  可能乘坐棕色通用货车
Well he disappeared this morning, probably on I-70
向I-70公路东边或西边去了
going east or west in a brown utility truck.
好的
Okay, ummm.
我发现大约两小时前70号公路上
I see one vehicle on I-70 going east
有一辆汽车从你所在的地点往东去了
through your location about two hours ago.
好  那个...
Okay, uh...
那肯定就是他们了
That...that's got to be them.
喂  喂
Hello? Hello?
该死的世界末日
Damn apocalypse.
你  在我们看得见的地方尿
Hey! Where we can see you.
有人看着我尿不出
I got a bashful bladder.
我管你尿得出尿不出
Don't mistake me for somebody who cares!
你好啊
Well, hello there.
市民Z  看看你到底有没有真本事
Citizen Z, are you as good as you think you are?
摩菲先生
Mr. Murphy!
快点过来
Get over here.
等我把最后几滴甩干净了
Just shaking the dew off the lily!
你在这呢  摩菲
There you are, Murphy.
一如既往的做派
Classy as ever.
沃伦说得对  你被绑架了
Warren was right. You've been kidnapped.
灾变之前你是干什么的
So you were what before the apocalypse?
干安保的
I worked security.
没错  我感觉得出来
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. I was getting that vibe.
哪一种  军人  特种部队  海豹突击队
Oh, so what? Military, Special Ops, Navy Seal?
闭嘴
Shut up!
又来了  又是个叉路口
Well here we go again, another fork in the road.
看不出来他们走的哪条路
Hard to tell which way they went.
市民Z  这里是三角洲X光小队  请回答
Citizen Z, this is Delta-Xray. Copy.
喂
Hello?
我想扔硬币看看  但是谁有硬币
I'd say flip a coin, but who's got coins?
这边
看看那个
Hey, check that out.
这边
也许这是市民Z给我们发的信息
Well maybe it's a message from our guy.
加油啊  意思是让你们走右边
Come on. Come on. It means go right!
走右边
Go right!
是啊  意思是他们走了那条路
Yeah. He's saying they went that way.
这边
走  我们出发
Yeah. Let's roll.
太好了
Yes!
非常感谢
大将军  要不要说说我们这是在干嘛
So General, wanna tell me what the hell we're doing?
从这再走6英里  过了那道岭
Six miles from here, up and over that peak,
就是梅撒制药的储运中心了
is the Mesa Pharmaceutical Storage and Transfer Facility.
惊天新闻啊
Stunning news.
忙完了之后  咱去迪士尼乐园好不好
And after that, can we please oh please go to Disneyland?
梅撒就是这个僵尸世界里的超级金库
Mesa is the Fort Knox of the Zombie Apocalypse.
里面储满了未开封的药品
It's filled with unused pharmaceuticals,
大部分都是奥施康定[镇痛药]  摩菲先生
mostly oxycontin Mr. Murphy,
你知道这世道药品有多金贵
you know the value of drugs in this world.
什么都能拿药来换  药品就是金钱
You can trade them for anything. They're money.
也就是说你想从梅撒手里拿些奥施康定
So you want to liberate some oxycontin from Mesa.
尽管拿啊
Be my guest.
里面全是僵尸
It's full of Zs.
几十个
Dozens.
其中有些速度非常快
Some of them are hopped up on speed.
那么摩菲先生
So Mr. Murphy,
你施展你那穿行于僵尸间的神通
you do your walk through zombies trick,
为我们把门打开  等我们拿了药出来
open the gates for us, and when we ride out
你就自由了
you're a free man.
你怎么不早说  我最爱奥施康定了
Well why didn't you just say so earlier? I love oxycontin.
我们为什么不坐车
Why do we have to go on foot?
磕了药的僵尸对声音非常敏感
Meth zombies are extremely responsive to sound.
所以我们只能轻手轻脚进去
So we can only sneak up if we're walking.
而且我还得把路堵上
And I want this road blocked
免得有别的什么车来惊动了僵尸
so some other vehicle doesn't drive in and set off the Zs.
亨利
Henry.
帮我处理一下卡车
Give me a hand with the truck.
我可不想走之后我们的车被人动手脚
I don't want it tampered with while we're gone.
刷新下限啊
A new low.
你刚才说什么
Did you say something?
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
在搞科研吗
Science project?
安全保护措施
Insurance policy.
我们要把车在这儿放一会
We have to leave this truck here for a while.
我希望回来的时候它还在这儿
I want it to be here when we get back.
这年头谁都不能信啊
You just can't trust anybody these days.
说得对
Copy that.
决战时刻到了
It's Zero Hour.
我看你戴着结婚戒指
I see you're wearing a wedding ring.
你丈夫呢
Your husband?
尸变了
Among the lost.
上次行动时他被僵尸咬了
The Zs got him last time we tried this.
你们以前就去抢过奥施康定吗
You guys tried robbing this oxy before?
一个月前
A month ago.
他跟兹默曼想出来的主意
He and Zimmerman cooked up the whole idea.
他叫什么名字
What was his name?
杰森
Jason.
你们结婚多久了
How long were you guys married?
五年了
Five years.
他是个警察
He was a cop.
别问个不停了  摩菲
Knock off the questions, Murphy.
这里不是婚恋网站
This isn't Match.com.
等一下
Hold up a minute.
我先去前面侦察一下  亨利
I'm gonna scout up ahead. Henry!
提防着点儿
Keep an eye out.
我们很快就会遇见僵尸了
We'll be expecting Zs soon.
你一定很难过吧
That must be tough.
你丈夫死了  可是野心勃勃的兹默曼却还活着
Your husband dead while a wannabe like Zimmerman lives.
杰森知道这事有风险
Jason knew the risks.
但是结果还是兹默曼从中获益最大
Still, it worked out pretty well for Zimmerman.
你什么意思
What are you saying?
没什么
Nothing.
只是想说你丈夫现在与僵尸为伍
Just your husband gets to walk among the dead
兹默曼却有你作伴
and Zimmerman gets you.
闭嘴
Shut up.
对不起
Sorry.
我这个人喜欢闲聊
I'm just a chatty Kathy.
我不是有意的
I didn't mean anything.
你们听到了吗
You hear that?
好像是枪响
That sounded like a gunshot.
是的
Sure did.
我们得小心点
Let's be careful.
嘿  把枪给我
Hey, hey! Give me that!
放手
Let go.
到底怎么回事  刚才谁开的枪
What the hell is going on here? Who fired that shot?
他想把枪抢过去  然后就走火了
He went for her gun and it went off.
是这样吗
Is that true?
不是
No.
是个意外  刚才我在上子弹的时候走火了
It was an accident. I was reloading and it just went off.
我只是好心帮忙  这个蠢货上来就拦我
I was just trying to be helpful, and this idiot tackles me.
行了  都别吵
All right, all of you.
别在这儿废话了  都给我团结点
Knock off the bullshit and pull yourselves together.
梅撒工厂就在前面
The Mesa plant is just ahead.
天黑之前我们要赶过去
We need to get going before it gets dark.
他们好像把车留在这儿了
Looks like they left their truck.
我们也要下车了
And we're gonna do the same.
有什么不对劲的吗
Something wrong?
总是不对劲
Always.
继续走
Keep moving.
第2552个
Two thousand, five hundred fifty-two.
多谢提醒
Thanks for the warning.
不客气
You're welcome.
他们知道我们跟上来了
They know we're coming now.
走吧
Let's go.
拜托了  咬痕研究所
Come on Operation Bitemark.
来点电波反应
Give me a wave.
发射个信号弹  或者给我发条信息
Send up a flare. Shoot me a text.
来个麦田怪圈也行  我只要知道你还健在就好
Crop circles. Anything to let me know you're still alive.
玛丽莲·莫奇搜索结果
Results for Marilyn Merch.
好的好的  我们还是能帮上点忙的
Okay, okay, we can do something useful.
莫奇医生  那里沦陷后你去哪了
So Dr. Merch, where were you when that was captured?
三个月前
Three months ago?
科罗拉多
Colorado?
科罗拉多有什么
What's in Colorado?
我们找到他之后怎么办
Well what are we gonna do when we find him?
看看这个
Hey, check this out.
你认为他是故意留在这的吗
You think he left it on purpose?
一定是
He must have.
他绝对不是自愿的
He definitely didn't go willingly.
我们最好快点
We better step it up.
我就知道她会这么说
I knew she was gonna say that.
该死
Damn it.
停  大家
Stop. Everyone.
早该休息了
About time.
别着急
Don't worry.
翻过去就到了
Our target is just over this ridge.
你的事也马上就完了
And your troubles will soon be over.
我可不喜欢他这么讲话
I don't like the way he said that.
你想要什么
You want something?
亨利  检查下附近
Henry, check the perimeter.
我可不希望有什么"惊喜"
I don't want any surprises.
你
You.
跟我过来
Over here with me.
为什么每个人都觉得可以指挥哥
Why does everybody think they can boss me around?
他们的速度更快了
They look even faster than last time.
你想让我从它们身边穿过去吗
You want me to walk through those?
它们就是僵尸界的尤赛恩·博尔特啊
They're like the Usain Bolts of zombies.
它们吃什么了  甲安菲他明[一种兴奋剂]吗
What are they on? Meth?
是利他林[中枢兴奋药]  它们喜欢那玩意
Actually ritalin. They love the stuff.
好极了  世界就需要这样的多动症僵尸
Great. Just what the world needs, ADHD zombies.
我们尝试过火拼  但是失败了
We tried a frontal assault and it failed,
詹尼斯的丈夫还因此献身
got Janice's husband killed.
但阁下您肯定能风度翩翩地从僵尸群中过
But you should be able to waltz right through all the Zs.
是啊  你是站着说话不腰疼啊
Oh yeah. You make it sound so easy.
我又没说那很容易
I never said it was easy.
只是觉得你能做到
Just possible.
听着  不幸的小士兵
Look here, soldier of misfortune.
哪怕哥死了  你也不在乎
You may not care if I get killed,
但哥打赌其余的人类肯定悲痛欲绝
but I'll bet the rest of humanity does.
哥才不要干这破事呢
There's no way I'm doing this.
我才不在乎你的生死或是其余的人类怎么想
I don't care about you or the rest of humanity.
狗娘养的杂种
Son of a bitch.
你敢咬我
You bit me.
应该现在就崩了你
I ought to shoot you right now.
但你下不了手啊
But you won't.
天啊
God.
我看见他了
I see him.
杰森
Jason!
是杰森
It's Jason.
你知道他可能在这的
You knew he might be here.
我一直努力不去想这件事
I'm trying not to think about it.
但事实就在眼前  我能想到的就是
But now it's happening, and all I can think is
是你害死了他
you're the one that got him killed.
你为什么不想想我是怎么把你救出来的
Why don't you think about how I saved your life?
决定了没有
What's it gonna be?
准备动手吧
Let's do this.
哥还赶着去其它地方呢
I've got some place to be.
这是什么
What is it?
看起来像个仓库
Looks like some kind of warehouse.
该死  是高速型僵尸
Damn. Those are fast Zs.
你认为这就是他们的目的地吗
You think that's where they're at?
肯定的
Must be.
好像是生产什么的工厂
Yeah, some kind of manufacturing plant.
梅撒制药
Mesa Pharmaceuticals.
所有的僵尸都聚集在这里
Oh, the Zs are all over this place.
有什么可笑的
What's so funny?
你自己看吧
See for yourself.
是什么
What is it?
你们都在看什么
What are you looking at?
显然
Apparently,
僵尸进入制药厂之后
the Zs got into the Pharmaceuticals.
有些僵尸嗑药后行动敏捷了
Some of them are on speed,
但还有不少僵尸看来嗑上"伟哥"爽起来了
but it looks like more than a few of them got into the viagra.
打死我也想不到竟有这种事
I had no idea that was even possible.
小万万啊  哥正式说一句
Kid, it's official.
该见识的你都见识过了
You have now seen it all.
梅撒制药公司
周围安全了
It's all clear.
很好  摩菲  该你上场了
Good. Murphy, this is your moment.
兹莫曼  僵尸们好像很高兴见到你啊
Zimmerman, looks like these Zs are happy to see you.
闭嘴
Shut up.
计划如下
Here's the plan.
经过拐角  去到第一个门  门没锁
Head for the first door past the corner. It'll be unlocked.
进去后  立即右拐
Go inside and immediately turn to your right.
你会看到笼子里电源  打开笼子
You'll see a power panel inside a cage. Open it.
启动主发电机
Turn on the main generator.
门  右走  笼子  发电机  还有吗
Door, right, cage, generator. Anything else?
一旦灯亮了
Once the lights are on,
径直走过你面前的房间
proceed directly across the room in front of you,
打开右侧门  进入储藏区
taking the right hand door into the storage area.
等一下  我是不是该拿笔记一下
All right. Should I be writing this down?
等你进去你就知道怎么走了
It'll all be obvious once you see it.
好吧
All right.
还有别的吗
Okay, anything else?
用不用我从那儿再给你带杯拿铁过来
Could I get you a chai latte? While I'm in there?
严肃点  你能否活命就看它了
Get serious. Your life depends on it.
到了备货区后  你走上一段楼梯
Once you're inside the staging area, you'll see an office
就能到达库存管理室
up a flight of stairs. That is inventory control.
走进去  找到报警器  拉动警报
Go inside, look for an alarm bell. Set it off.
警报声引开门口的僵尸  我们就能进去了
That'll draw the Zs away from the gate so we can get inside.
把货车的钥匙给我  他们会...
Then bring me the keys to the van. They'll be...
杰森
Jason!
杰森已经不在了
Jason's gone.
看他变成这幅模样
That must be hard,
你心里一定很难过
seeing him like this
而害他变成这样的人却还跟你生活在一起
and living with the man responsible.
还不到时候
Not just yet.
你说开始我们就开始  头儿
Ready when you are, General.
还等什么  快去
What are you waiting for? Go!
我迟早会查明真相的
It's only a matter of time until I know everything,
所以  你不如现在就告诉我吧
so you might as well just tell me now.
这世上没有秘密  至少瞒不住我
There are no secrets, not from me.
好了  莫奇医生
Okay, Doctor Merch.
为何你如此神秘
Why all the mystery?
你是基因重组方面的神童
You're the whiz kid genetic recombiner,
胜过哈佛大学的精英
like a shot out of Harvard.
你的基因剪接法创造了奇迹
Your gene splicing methods made miracles possible.
就在末日来临的两年之前
Then two years before the apocalypse,
你失踪了
you disappear.
消失了
Vanish.
无影无踪
Fall down a well.
直到三年后  僵尸爆发
Until three years after the shit goes down,
你又重新出现在
you resurface at the
朴茨茅斯大学的突发传染病实验室里
Portsmouth emergency infection lab,
给犯人注射实验疫苗
injecting prisoners with experimental vaccines.
看看这里有什么
Now what do we have here?
申请未经授权
Unauthorized request.
目前授权申请确认已经不可能了
Requested identification not available at this time.
不过很显然他们还没见识到哥的厉害
Apparently they don't know who they're dealing with.
摩菲进到那里面干什么
What in the hell is Murphy doing down there?
僵尸把他当做自己人
The Zs must think he's one of them.
所以兹莫曼和其他人才绑架了他
That must be why Zimmerman and the others kidnapped him,
这样他们就能利用他拿到药品了
so they can get to the drugs.
我跟他们一样都视药如命
Now I like drugs as much as the next guy,
但就算全世界的毒品都摆在那儿
but there ain't enough dope in the world that's gonna make
我也不会跑到伟哥僵尸的身边晃悠
me want to be out there walkin' around with them viagra Zs.
走吧
Let's go.
向右走  向右走
To the right. To the right.
看见笼子了
And cage.
行动缓慢的僵尸
Slow ones.
真没想到见到你们会这么开心
Never thought I'd be happy to see you guys.
好了
Okay.
主电源  主电源
Main power. Main power.
主电源  主...
Main power. Main...
谢谢  我相信我会试试那个
Well thank you. I believe I will try that one.
好
Okay.
第二步
Step two.
入场券在此
Now that's the ticket.
国安局官网
NSA.Org.
回话
Come in.
回话  北极光
Come in, Northern Light.
摩菲呼叫市民Z
This is Murphy for Citizen Z.
你这没用的王八蛋
Where are you,
死哪儿去了
you useless bastard.
回话  北极光
Come in, Northern Light.
你还活着
You're alive.
是的  不托你的福
Yeah, no thanks to you.
我现在没时间跟你聊天
Look. I don't have time to chit chat.
我这里出了状况
I'm in the middle of a situation here.
你找到莫奇医生了吗
Have you found Doctor Merch?
加州的实验室怎么回事
And what's going on with this lab in California?
我还没找到莫奇的所在地
I still don't have a location for Merch.
我最后的对话记录是
Last contact I have on record,
她在去加州的途中经过
she was en route to California by way of
科罗拉多州柯林斯堡
Fort Collins, Colorado.
在那之后就失去联系了
The trail goes dark after that.
为什么是哪里
Why there?
我不清楚
I'm not clear.
她停在一个军事基地
Her transport landed at a military base,
也许是补给燃料  也许是接其他乘客
maybe to refuel, maybe to pick up more passengers.
我不知道
I don't know.
无法确定  我还在调查
There's nothing conclusive, but I am still digging.
把她找出来
Just find her.
瞧这一切
Look at all this.
美极了  老兄  你做到了
Beautiful, man. You did it.
找奥施康定
Find the oxy.
搬到车上去
Get it into the van.
摩菲快下来  任务还没完成呢
Murphy! Get down here! The job's not done yet!
把钥匙拿到车上去
And bring the keys to the van!
有工作要做
Duty calls.
我马上来
I'm comin'.
过来这里帮忙  事情才能更快完成
Get over here and help. Things will go faster.
我不是你的搬货男
I am not your stock boy.
我没时间跟你啰嗦
I don't have time for this.
把枪放下
Drop it!
办不到  沃伦  你最好在我杀了
Not happening, Warren. You need to turn around
你的大包裹之前赶紧转身离开这里
and get out of here before I kill your big ticket.
那么你要怎样离开这里
Then how will you get out of here?
我们会开车
We can drive.
不知道你们会怎么做
Don't know what you folks will do.
好吧
Well,
既然麻烦都解决了  我们又回到起点了
now that that's over, we're right back where we started.
不管你想怎么玩  沃伦  你都必输无疑
What's the game, Warren? You are on a losing end.
事实上  情况和你说的正相反
Actually this is totally different.
你弱爆了  兹莫曼
You're weak, Zimmerman.
你个弱爆了的小跟班
You're a weak little man.
我们该阻止他们吗
Should we stop them?
除非他用枪指着摩菲
Only if he points that gun at Murphy.
你打算把我和其他人杀了
You were gonna kill me and the others.
真可悲
Pathetic.
现在是末世嘛
It's the apocalypse.
末世没有你会更好
The apocalypse is better off without you.
摩菲  你在干什么
Murphy, what are you doing?
我吗
Me?
没什么
Nothing.
摩菲
Murphy.
怎么了
What?
刚才谢谢你
Mercy granted.
我想你没必要道谢
I'm not sure that was necessary.
出发
Go!
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译 米小勒   kiko   CS小明漫画家   lottie  章鱼
翻译 我叫魏碧慧   蔡茸茸   S很爱笑   迷失_绽放
时间轴   SumenQ   安妮   太太乐叽叽     后期   阿小小海
校对   米小勒       总监   米小勒
僵 尸
国 度
.
第一季 第十二集